## Nithya Devi Chandrasekaran

Address. 85635, Höhenkirchen-Siegertsbrunn

Mobile +49 1573 0106001

Email <u>nithyadevi.ch@gmail.com</u>

Visa Status Long term Employment Permitted

LinkedIn <u>LinkedIn</u> GitHub <u>GitHub</u>



#### **Profile**

Front end Developer with 7+ years of experience in IT industry in various domains such as Insurance, Transport and Logistics. I started my career as an Ingenium developer and worked as a tester in Ingenium, SAP ERP and Siebel CRM systems. Received company award for achieving 100% SLA and many team appreciations.

IT Skills HTML,CSS, Javascript, React, Manual Testing, Siebel CRM testing, SAP ERP testing, Ingenium,MS-Office, MSSQL, JIRA, Root Cause Analysis, Defect fixing

## **Work Experience**

11.2021 - 12.2022	Integration in Deutschland, Volkshochschule
11.2021 - 12.2022	integration in Deutschland, <b>Volkshothisthule</b>

(Munich, Germany) German Language courses and TELC Examination with B1 qualification

# **06.2015 - 03.2018** Resource Specialist, **Pragya Living Wisdom Centre**

(Bangalore, India) Executed the curriculum, documented the lesson plans, tracked student's progress and conducted individual parent meetings

#### **06.2010 - 06.2015** A

(Bangalore, India)

#### Associate, Cognizant Technology Solutions PVT Ltd

- Handled Customer service functions through the Siebel CRM e-business applications
- Customer account creation, fare media purchase, service requests creation and inventory management for Call-Center Application
- Owned SAP Visual Composer Module with key accountability in ERP product releases
- Mentored Junior resources, led Regression testing team interacting with product owners and developers

#### 08.2007 - 05.2010

(Chennai, India)

## Programmar Analyst, Cognizant Technology Solutions PVT Ltd

- Performed analysis, coding, test case preparation, unit testing of MetLife's BIOS system and Max New York life.
- Developed the Life Line Series Product, provided data fix and code fix within SLA
- Received company award for completion of tickets achieving 100%
  SLA. Handled internal Audits as part of Quality Assurance team

## **Education**

**08.2005 - 06.2007** (*Chennai, India*)

Masters in Chemical Engineering, Anna University

08.2001 - 06.2005

Bachelors in Pharmaceutical Engineering, Bharathidasan University

(Trichirapalli, India)

**Courses** 

**03.2023 - Present** (*Munich,Germany*)

Frontend DevelopmentCourse, ReDI school

**Soft Skills** 

Information and data literacy, Data Input, Communication and

collaboration, Problem solving

**Publication** 

Published a paper in Indian Pharmaceutical Journal

https://www.ijpsonline.com/articles/wound-healing-activity-of-

cyperus-rotundus-linn.html?view=mobile

Authors: A.PURATCHIKODY\*, C.NITHYADEVI AND G. NAGALAKSHMI

Languages

English (Fluent)

German (B1)

Tamil (Native)